## **JASON HUEY**

www.linkedin.com/in/jhueyx | Mobile: (415) 418-9774 | Email: hello@jhuey.com

#### **SNAPSHOT**

**SKILLS** 

Jason Huey is a motivated professional with extensive experience in the financial services industry and experience in the hypergrowth stage start-up environment managing fraud and risk operations. He has experience with developing and driving initiatives from concept to implementation.

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# MARQETA INC-Oakland, CA

## Lead Risk Analyst, Transaction Monitoring

July 2020- Present

- Identified and investigated high risk/suspicious transactions and taking appropriate action as the program manager for each partner program
- Coordinated with Issuing Banks and Programs to ensure that Marqeta remains compliant with their requirements for transaction monitoring, reporting and dispute resolution
- Reviewed unemployment benefit credits for legitimacy and accuracy
- ❖ Investigated ACH credits for money laundering and/or fraudulent activity
- Leveraged experience with On-Demand/Gig Economy transactions to work on partner program risk strategies targeting expense card unauthorized transactions

#### UBER TECHNOLOGIES INC. - San Francisco, CA

#### **Decision Scientist II, Money Movement Risk**

April 2019- June 2020

- Managed product launch risk strategy for nascent launch product on UberEats as well as driving strategy on mitigating risk in money movement, and contractor prepaid card risk mitigation
- Helped launch product and enabling fraud prevention on product targeted to unlock selection for users
- Worked cross-functionally with engineering, product, and various operations team to drive project launch
- Analyze user and transaction data to drive business decisions to contribute to rule writing and machine learning
- Designed optimal risk actions that strike a balance between growth and risk controls

#### PINTEREST INC. - San Francisco, CA

Associate Data Scientist, Payment Operations & Fraud (Contract)

September 2018- April 2019

- Monitored credit processing and reviewed escalated transactions for domestic/international fraud
- Review credit card usage on the platform and review new advertiser accounts for fraud and spam
- Reported any trends or anomalies noticed & suggest ideas which can be implemented to catch frauds & reduce chargeback
- Leverage SQL for data analysis to support and execute strategies to detect fraud, account takeovers and payment anomalies
- Identified multiple account takeover (ATO) attacks impacting advertisers, payment cardholders, as well as Pinterest users

## POSTMATES INC. - San Francisco, CA

Senior Manager, Head of Marketplace Trust & Risk Strategy

June 2014 – April 2018

- Lead for Postmates' Risk Team oversaw insurance, fraud, payment operations, and security on the Postmates platform
- Founding architect for the Postmates Trust & Safety program- provided guidelines and process for the entire marketplace to ensure the safety of all users and to protect the company from all losses
- Liaised with internal and external counsels and TPAs on workers' compensation, unemployment, disability, civil, and other general risk areas
- Minimized payment fraud with risk initiatives created by using a combination of in-house fraud rules and tools provided by payment and fraud-detection vendors and provided insights on trends for chargebacks, failed payment fraud, and contractor prepaid card fraud
- Created internal tools to mitigate fraud exposures, and monitor quality of fleet monetary exposures with SQL and BI tools
- Investigated on all escalated tickets including law enforcement and third-party data requests
- Managed various legal projects around garnishments, unemployment, workers' compensation, tax compliance and other finance related projects

## SIGFIG WEALTH MANAGEMENT, LLC. - San Francisco, CA

#### Consultant, Product Strategy & Onboarding

February 2014- May 2014

- Managed daily operations with launch of managed investment product by reviewing brokerage documents from clients and submitting to institutional broker dealers (TD Ameritrade, Charles Schwab, and Fidelity)
- Reviewed documentations such as new account applications, power of attorney, asset transfer requests and letters of instructions
- Leveraged information as an investment professional to help the operations team to be following regulations

## JPMORGAN CHASE BANK, N.A. - San Francisco, CA & Daly City, CA

#### Vice President, Private Client Banker

February 2010 - February 2014

- Transitioned into a sales role after spending six years in branch operations, and obtained investment licenses within first year as a personal banker
- Provided exceptional service through a dedicated team with exclusive access to J.P. Morgan's investment expertise
- Profiled and discovered clients' financial needs and provided recommendations of bank products and investment vehicles
- Deepened relationships with clients through the process of relationship management and deepened the importance and value of Chase Private Client
- ❖ Adhered to policies, procedures and regulatory banking requirements

#### Assistant Vice President, Branch Operations Manager

July 2004 – February 2010

- First started as an intern and moved into the operations supervisor role after graduating from high school
- Coordinated branch operations and compliance meetings, communicating on updates for operations, compliance and sales
- Provided support to teller staff and bankers on transactional approvals such as new employee limits, wire transfer approvals, as well as exceptions
- Supervised 7-10 branch employees including teller staff, bankers, loan agents, and investment advisors
- Financial instrument custodianship maintaining controls on traveler's checks, money orders, gift cards, and legal check stock
- ATM and vault custodianship maintaining controls on the branch vault, cash dispensers, and ATM
  machines
- Prepared branch for internal audits and external (OCC) audits

## **EDUCATION**

# CODIFY ACADEMY - San Francisco, CA

**Certificate of Front-End Web Development** 

May 2018 - September 2018

## SAN FRANCISCO STATE UNIVERSITY - San Francisco, CA

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, Concentration in Finance

August 2006 – March 2010